mymotherlode.com 2019-03-31

# myMotherLode.com Privacy Policy - Sonora Mother Lode | myMotherLode.com

A Privacy Policy Statement from Clarke Broadcasting Corporation (“Clarke”) and Your California Privacy Rights

Last updated and effective, June 1st 2018. Our Terms of Service are [here.](https://www.mymotherlode.com/terms-of-service)

This policy will let you know:

  1. [Information We Collect And How We Use the Information](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#collect)
  2. [Cookies & Web Beacons, What Cookies Are, What They Collect](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#coookies)
    1. [Types of Cookies We Use on Our Website](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#types)
  3. [Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers, and Sponsors](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#thirdparty)
  4. [Note for Parents](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#parents)
  5. [Legal Grounds for Using (Processing) Your Information](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#legal)
  6. [Transfer Information to the United States](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#us)
  7. [How to Contact Us](https://www.mymotherlode.com/privacy-policy#contact)

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for Clarke’s web properties, including our websites and mobile/tablet applications (each, a “Website”). Your continued use of a Website following the posting of changes to this privacy policy statement means you accept those changes.

**The Information We Collect**

At a Website, you may be able to enter contests, vote in polls or otherwise express an opinion, sign up to receive a newsletter, purchase a “classified” advertisement, browse the embedded content of our third party partners, or participate in one of our online forums or communities. In connection with such activities, we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personally identifiable information. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected at these pages include: name, address, zip code, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, gender, birth date, and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services. In addition, some Clarke websites offer the ability to integrate with third party websites, in which case you may have an opportunity to voluntarily provide additional identifiable information.

At certain parts of a Website, only persons who provide us with the requested personally identifiable information will be able to participate in programs and services or otherwise participate in the site’s activities and offerings. Our third party partners may process payment and banking information that you provide to them. Clarke has a Credit Card Security Policy that you may request for review via our [feedback form](https://www.mymotherlode.com/feedback).

We also may collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you visit many of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Firefox or Google Chrome), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Windows or Mac OS), the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., Verizon FiOS or Comcast), and the search engine from which you were directed (e.g., Google or Bing). Each Website utilizes analytical software, including Google Analytics or other analytical software, which may collect information about users.

Each Website does not follow the Do Not Track setting of a user’s web browser.

**How We Use the Information**

If you provide us with your e-mail address, or have done so in the past, we may send you e-mail offers, surveys, newsletters, or other types of contacts. These are based on information you provided in your registration forms, in surveys, from information that may indicate purchasing preferences and lifestyle, as well as information available from external sources, such as census bureau data. If you have signed up to receive our e-mails and prefer not to receive marketing information from this site, follow the “unsubscribe” instructions provided on any marketing e-mail you receive from the Website.

We sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when you have won one of our contests, to fulfill a request by you, or to send you an online newsletter if you have signed up for a newsletter.

We also use information generally to compile statistical and user profile data and to keep in contact with users and provide them with a better interactive experience. We may use your information specifically for the following purposes: to provide a desktop version of the site for easy access with a mobile phone every time you return to the site without requiring re-entry of the desktop preference; to complete business transactions; to contact you as part of a promotion; to allow you to make a posting on the site; to administer individual classified accounts; to provide customer support; to meet legal requirements; to provide Internet security; and/or to analyze collected information.

In the event that Clarke sells a Website or business associated with a Website, all user/listener/customer information relating to a Website or Clarke business may be among the transferred assets.

We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage.

We work closely with our business partners and certain other third parties who may perform functions on our behalf, including but not limited to fulfilling orders, providing promotional materials to our users, sending e-mail, managing data, processing credit card payments, or providing customer service. They have access to your personal information to perform their functions and may not use it for any other purpose.

Notwithstanding any provision of this Privacy Policy to the contrary, to the extent you provide your information, we will not sell or rent such information to any third party unless you otherwise specifically consent.

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

We keep your information for no longer than necessary for the purposes for which it is processed. The length of time for which we retain information depends on the purposes for which we collected and use it and/or as required to comply with applicable laws.

Finally, we may disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law. In addition, we may transfer information about you if we are acquired by or merged with another company.

**Cookies& Web Beacons**

We use and allow certain other companies to use certain tracking technologies, including cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies (collectively, “Cookies”) on a Website. This section (“Cookie Notice”) explains what these technologies are and why we use them, as well as your rights to control our use of them. We endeavor to adhere to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) self-regulatory principles governing interest-based advertising.

We use Cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our sites. Our third party partners may also use Cookies.

**What are Cookies?**  
Cookies are text files that contain a certain amount of information and are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. They are useful because they allow websites to recognize a user’s device. They are then returned to the original website on each subsequent visit or to any other website that recognizes them. For more information on Cookies, go to [http://www.allaboutCookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Types of Information We Collect**  
Cookies help us to understand Website usage and to improve the content and offerings on our Website and in other media. Examples of the types of information that we collect through Cookies include: the number of users visiting a Website, the number of times a Website was viewed, the pages viewed, the clicks made on a Website and the total duration of navigation on a Website; the name of the page that referred you to the Website; whether this is your first time visiting a Website; your user name, your password, the type of browser used, and your IP address, so that we can identify you during your next visits.

How We Use Cookies Examples of ways that we or our third party partners may use Cookies include:

  *  To control the display of ads;
  *  To track usage patterns on a Website;
  *  To deliver editorial content;
  *  To record requests for newsletters;
  *  To prevent manipulation of our polls
  *  To implement our affiliate marketing program; and
  *  To personalize information.

Clarke (or third party service providers on our behalf) may also use Cookies to collect aggregate information about Website users on an anonymous basis. We may share demographic and usage information with our prospective and actual business partners, advertisers, and other third parties for any business purpose.

**Types of Cookies We Use on Our Website**

We use first party and third party Cookies for several reasons. Some Cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our Site to operate, and we refer to these as “essential” or “strictly necessary” Cookies. Third parties also serve Cookies through our Website for advertising, analytics, and other purposes. The specific types of first and third party Cookies served through our Website and the functions they perform are described in more detail below.

**First-party Cookies** These Cookies are created by Clarke. They allow you to browse a Website and use its features.

**Essential Cookies:** These Cookies are necessary to allow you to move around a Website and use its features, such as accessing your posted “classified” advertisement. Without these Cookies, we cannot enable appropriate content based on the type of device you are using. Therefore, these Cookies cannot be disabled.

**Embedded Scripts:** An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with a Website, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your computer or other device, is active only while you are connected to a Website, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**Analytics Cookies:** We use Cookies and other identifiers (such as web beacons) to see how you use our Websites in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to the preferences of our customers and visitors. For example, Cookies and web beacons may be used to maintain a consistent look and feel across our Websites, track and provide trend analysis on how our users interact with our Websites, track errors, and measure the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns. You may refuse these Cookies in your browser settings. To refuse these Cookies, you may install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on by clicking [here.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

**Third-Party Cookies**  
Some of our third party partners (including advertisers and marketing services companies) may set and access Cookies on your computer as well, or we may do so on their behalf. We do not have control over how these third parties use such Cookies and similar technologies or the information derived therefrom, and this Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information that such third parties may have collected from you or the methods used by the third-parties to collect that information. These types of Cookies include:

**Advertising Cookies:** These Cookies, defined exclusively by third parties, collect several types of data about your browsing habits, as well as your preferences for products and services. This information allows third parties to serve you relevant advertisements on our Websites. Some advertisements may also contain an icon that you may click on to find out more about how to manage your advertising preferences, or you may be able to refuse these Cookies by adjusting your browser settings.

**Third-Party Functional Cookies:** These Cookies are defined by third parties who support our Websites and allow you to use useful services and features. To refuse these Cookies, please adjust your browser settings.

As of the Effective Date above, the third party partners include the following. This list may be updated from time to time:

Ad Servers

  * Google Analytics
  * OpenX
  * Add This
  * Adblade
  * Financialcontent.com

Tracking Vendors

  * Exponential (Tribal Fusion)
  * Chartbeat
  * Outbrain
  * TrustArc
  * Quantcast
  * Getadmiral.com

Other

  * Authorize.net
  * IMDB
  * Inform.com
  * Big Fish Games
  * IDX Broker
  * Mail Chimp
  * LevelOne Web Design
  * Yellow Pages
  * On the Snow
  * iPublish
  * Oracle

For more about third-party ad servers generally visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s website at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers, and Sponsors**

Some of Clarke’s Websites contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites’ privacy policies as Clarke has no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

The Clarke sites covered by this Privacy Policy sometimes may offer content (e.g., contests, sweepstakes, or promotions) that are sponsored by or cobranded with identified third parties. Information collected by Clarke in connection with entering, voting or otherwise participating in any contest, sweepstakes, or promotions, may be shared with sponsors of such contests. By entering, voting or otherwise participating in such contests, you are consenting to us sharing this information with such contest sponsors who may contact you directly. Clarke has no control over these third parties’ use of this information. Exponential Interactive, Inc, as our partner, has a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review their privacy policy or contact their data protection officer via privacy@exponential.com.

**The following only applies to California residents:**

Clarke may from time to time share your personal information with its subsidiaries or affiliates. Clarke may also from time to time share your personal information with Clarke’s sponsors, partners, advertisers, or other third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you do not want us to share your personal information with such third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please let us know by contacting us using our feedback [form here](https://www.mymotherlode.com/feedback) or by mail at Clarke Broadcasting Corporation, Attn: Internet Privacy Manager, 342 S Washington St, Sonora, CA 95370. We will process your opt-out request within 30 days of our receipt.

**Note for Parents**

Clarke does not knowingly solicit data from children, and we will not knowingly market to children. Clarke adheres to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). Clarke’s websites are general audience websites which are not directed to children generally, including children under the age of 13. It is our policy to discard any information which is obtained from any child who is under the age of 13.

**Legal Grounds for Using (Processing) Your Information**

If you are a visitor from the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using the information described above will depend on the information concerned and the context in which we collect it.

**We collect information from you:**

1\. where we need it to perform our contract with you (i.e., our Terms of Service),

2\. where the processing is in our legitimate interests (provided that these are not overridden by your interests or rights) such as personalizing our services and marketing for example, or

3\. if we otherwise have your consent.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your information, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How To Contact Us” section below.

**Transfer Information to the United States**

Our websites operate in the United States of America (USA) and are intended for users located in the USA. If you are located outside of the USA, please note that the information you provide to us will be transferred to and processed in the USA, where laws regarding processing of personal data may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

**How to Contact Us**

For instructions on how you can access the personally identifiable information that Clarke has collected about you online, how to correct factual errors in such information, or if you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or its implementation you may contact us at:

Clarke Broadcasting Corporation 342 S.Washington St. Sonora CA, 95370

Attn: Internet Privacy Manager

Or via [our feedback form](https://www.mymotherlode.com/feedback)

**Updates & Effective Date**

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this policy so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it.
